<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="api-application-call-center">
    <title>Call Center APIs</title>
    <shortdesc>Connect Call Center System and <ph keyref="product_name"/> via API to achieve
        multiple operations, such as automatic call distribution, agent management, daily
        communication, and satisfaction survey.</shortdesc>
    <body>
        <dl>
            <dlentry>
                <dt>Scenario</dt>
                <dd>
                    <p>Call Center System is important for a company to increase customer retention
                        and brand loyalty, improve service quality &amp; efficiency, and enhance
                        competitiveness. Along with the development of Internet, many SMBs (Small
                        and Medium-sized enterprises) and cross-regional enterprises have wondered
                        how to simultaneously achieve the integration of Call Center System and
                        Internet, and address the high cost of distributed establishment. With <ph
                            keyref="product_name"/> API, you can integrate Call Center System with
                        PBX. The PBX can replace the expensive ACD (Automatic Call Distributor), and
                        provide better compatibility with CTI (Computer Telephony Integration).
                        Operations like agent management, automatic call distribution, and
                        satisfaction survey are accessible.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
        </dl>
        <section id="section_bk2_2j5_xjb">
            <title>Queue settings</title>
            <ul id="ul_rcq_cjr_dlb">
                <li><b>Add a queue</b><p>Add various queues for various service types. Incoming
                        calls will be routed to the specified queue.</p><p>
                        <ol>
                            <li>Log in PBX web page, and go to <menucascade>
                                    <uicontrol>Settings</uicontrol>
                                    <uicontrol> PBX</uicontrol>
                                    <uicontrol> Call Features</uicontrol>
                                    <uicontrol> Queue</uicontrol>
                                </menucascade>.</li>
                            <li>Set static agents or dynamic agents.<p>Dynamic agents can log in and
                                    log out of queue via API. We recommend that members work as
                                    dynamic agents.</p></li>
                            <li>Set ring strategy.<p>Automatic Call Distributor (ACD) is recommended
                                    in Call Center System to help manage call traffic and distribute
                                    calls. You can select <uicontrol>Least Recent</uicontrol> or
                                        <uicontrol>Fewest Calls</uicontrol>.</p><p><image
                                        href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-add-queue.png"
                                        width="650" id="image_i1n_jhx_dlb"/></p></li>
                        </ol>
                    </p></li>
                <li><b>Query queue settings</b><p>After adding a queue on PBX, administrator can
                        query queue information on Call Center System, such as queue number, queue
                        name, and queue agents.</p><p>
                        <ol id="ol_r2r_xkr_dlb">
                            <li>When administrator checks queue information on Call Center System,
                                the system sends a quest to API interface to query queue list.</li>
                            <li>After receiving the request, PBX sends queue list to Call Center
                                System.</li>
                        </ol>
                    </p><p> For API interface, refer to <xref href="queue-query.dita"/></p><p><image
                            href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-query-queue.png"
                            id="image_fzb_gty_dlb" width="650"/></p></li>
                <li><b>Update queue settings</b><p>Administrator can update queue settings on Call
                        Center System, such as ring strategy, static agents, key destination and so
                        on.</p><ol id="ol_zpt_fkr_dlb">
                        <li>When administrator updates queue settings on Call Center System, the
                            system sends a queue-update request to API interface.</li>
                        <li>After receiving the request, PBX updates queue settings, and responds
                            result to Call Center System.</li>
                    </ol><p> For API interface, refer to <xref href="queue-update.dita"
                            />.</p><p><image
                            href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-modify-queue.png" width="650"
                            id="image_ypq_jvy_dlb"/></p></li>
            </ul>
            <ul id="ul_osl_kpr_dlb">
                <li><b>Check queue status</b><p>Administrator can check call status and agent status
                        of a specific queue.</p><p>
                        <ol id="ol_oym_14r_dlb">
                            <li>Administrator checks call status of queue 6700 on Call Center
                                System, the system sends a queue-query request to API
                                interface.</li>
                            <li>After receiving the request, PBX sends the call status of queue 6700
                                to Call Center System.</li>
                        </ol>
                    </p><p> For API interface, refer to <xref href="queuestatus-query.dita"
                            />.</p><p><image
                            href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-check-queue-status.png"
                            width="650" id="image_dkg_cyy_dlb"/></p><p>
                        <note>With <uicontrol>Status Monitor</uicontrol> enabled on API, when the
                            extension status changes, PBX sends a <xref
                                href="event-ExtensionStatus.dita">'Extension Status'</xref> Report
                            of the agent to Call Center System. Administrator can check agent status
                            in real time.</note>
                    </p></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section id="section_p3n_dlr_dlb">
            <title>Agent operations</title>
            <p>
                <ul id="ul_apr_flr_dlb">
                    <li><b>Log in a queue</b><p>An agent starts to work when he/she logs in a queue.
                            The system routes calls to the agent when receiving incoming calls.</p><p>
                            <ol id="ol_h5d_ttr_dlb">
                                <li>When an agent logs in a queue on Call Center System, the system
                                    sends a login request to API interface.</li>
                                <li>After receiving the request, PBX processes agent login, and
                                    responds result to Call Center System.</li>
                            </ol>
                        </p><p>For API interface, refer to <xref href="queue-add-dynamicagent.dita"
                                >Log in a Queue</xref>.</p><p><image
                                href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-agent-login.png" width="650"
                                id="image_abl_ycz_dlb"/></p></li>
                    <li><b>Log out of a queue</b><p>An agent can log out of a queue when he/she
                            finishes work. The system stops routing calls to the agent.<ol
                                id="ol_lls_fvr_dlb">
                                <li>When an agent logs out of a queue on Call Center System, the
                                    system sends a logout request to API interface.</li>
                                <li>After receiving the request, PBX processes agent logout, and
                                    responds result to Call Center System.</li>
                            </ol></p><p>For API interface, refer to <xref
                                href="queue-del-dynamicagent.dita">Log out a
                                Queue</xref>.</p><p><image
                                href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-agent-logout.png"
                                id="image_snf_pdz_dlb" width="650"/></p></li>
                    <li><b>Pause an agent's service</b><p>When an agent is not available or takes a
                            short break, the agent can temporarily pause service. The system will
                            not route calls to the agent.</p><p>
                            <ol id="ol_r5b_brr_dlb">
                                <li>When an agent pauses service on Call Center System, the system
                                    sends a pause request to API interface.</li>
                                <li>After receiving the request, PBX pauses the agent's service, and
                                    responds result to Call Center System.</li>
                            </ol>
                        </p><p>For API interface, refer to <xref href="queue-pause-agent.dita"
                            />.</p><p><image
                                href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-agent-pause.png" width="650"
                                id="image_isj_32z_dlb"/></p></li>
                    <li><b>Resume an agent's service</b><p>An agent can resume service when he/she
                            becomes available again. The system will automatically route incoming
                            calls to the agent.<ol id="ol_owx_k5r_dlb">
                                <li>When an agent resumes service on Call Center System, the system
                                    sends a request to API interface to resume the agent's
                                    service.</li>
                                <li>After receiving the request, PBX resumes the agent's service,
                                    and responds result to Call Center System.</li>
                            </ol></p><p>For API interface, refer to <xref
                                href="queue-unpause-agent.dita"/>.</p><p><image
                                href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-agent-resume.png"
                                width="650" id="image_q2b_kgz_dlb"/></p></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_dsx_cl5_xjb">
            <title>Call features</title>
            <ul id="ul_tbr_w5r_dlb">
                <li><b>Make an outbound call</b><p>To follow up with customers, an agent can
                        directly call customers back.</p><p>
                        <ol id="ol_dpn_tbs_dlb">
                            <li>An agent makes an outbound call from Call Center System, the system
                                sends a call request to API interface.</li>
                            <li>After receiving the request, PBX rings the agent's extension first.
                                When the agent answers the call, PBX will ring customer's
                                phone.</li>
                        </ol>
                    </p><p>For API interface, refer to <xref href="call-dial.dita"/>.</p><p><image
                            href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-make-outbound-call.png"
                            width="650" id="image_hlg_snz_dlb"/></p></li>
                <li><b>Make an internal call</b><p>
                        <ol id="ol_hrr_kcs_dlb">
                            <li>An agent makes an internal call to another agent from Call Center
                                System, the system sends a call request to API interface.</li>
                            <li>After receiving the request, PBX rings the caller's extension first.
                                When the caller answers the call, PBX will ring the callee's
                                extension.</li>
                        </ol>
                    </p><p>For API interface, refer to <xref href="call-dial.dita"/>.</p><p><image
                            href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-call-extension.png" width="650"
                            id="image_wy5_m4z_dlb"/></p></li>
                <li><b>Automated outbound dialing</b><p>For telephone sales, Call Center System can
                        automatically make outbound calls to customers. When customers answer calls,
                        PBX will automatically route calls to agents. Automated outbound dialing
                        frees agents from demanding dialing operations, and improves agents' work
                        efficiency.</p><ol id="ol_wvj_pcs_dlb">
                        <li>Call Center System sends a request to API interface to make an outbound
                            call.</li>
                        <li>After receiving the request, PBX rings a customer first. After customer
                            answers the call, PBX will route the call to an agent in a queue.</li>
                    </ol><p>For API interface, refer to <xref href="call-dial.dita"/>.</p><p><image
                            href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-queue-auto-dial.png" width="650"
                            id="image_ldk_5pz_dlb"/></p></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section id="section_llg_khr_dlb">
            <title>Satisfaction survey</title>
            <p>After an agent ends a call, Call Center System prompts customers to join satisfaction
                survey. Customer Satisfaction Survey provides invaluable information about the
                quality and effectiveness of the service that customers receive, and helps agents
                improve service quality.<ol id="ol_gvh_b3s_dlb">
                    <li>When an agent ends a call, the system plays a satisfaction survey prompt to
                        customer. Customer presses keys to rate the service according to
                        prompt.</li>
                    <li>Based on gathered key information, PBX generates a <xref
                            href="event-satisfaction.dita">Satisfaction</xref> Report, and sends the
                        report to Call Center System.</li>
                </ol></p>
            <p><image href="../Images/pbx-api/api-call-center-customer-satisfaction.png" width="650"
                    id="image_svk_dsz_dlb"/></p>
        </section>
    </body>
</topic>
